Gauray Parmar

CONTACT

gauravparmariam@gmail.com

INFORMATION https://www.linkedin.com/in/gauravbparmar

https://gauravparmar.github.io Mob: +91-7892722061, 9479988064

#36/1, 5th Cross, PWD Road, B Narayanapura, Bangalore, Karnataka, India-560016

OBJECTIVE

Continuous progress on both professional and personal fronts through all-round skills and earn a position which provides me self-development and translate my experience, domain knowledge, analytical skills and abilities into value for consistent growth of the company I work with and to help society by solving real life problems by means of technology.

SUMMARY

Senior Full Stack Developer with 6+ years of expertise in building and designing large scale and scalable Web Apps and APIs for Mobile and Web Apps.

SKILLS

Backend Development : PHP, CakePHP, NodeJS(Learning)

Frontend Development: Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS(Learning)

CMS: Drupal 7, WordPress

DBMS: MySQL Programming: C, C++

Graphic Designing: Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

• Master of Technology (Integrated [5.5 years]) in Information Technology

International Institute of Professional Studies, DAVV, Indore

Jul 2010-Dec 2015

CGPA: 9.48/10

EMPLOYMENT

• Senior Software Engineer | Edureka

Aug 2018 – Present

Working on Edureka website which offers online live/self-paced courses which can be attended from any part of the world. Also working on the admin panels and APIs empowering this company's large scale Edutech system.

• Full Stack Developer | Trendsetter (Cosi Games), Bangalore

July 2017 – March 2018

Worked a big scale international product on both front-end and back-end consisting web panels and APIs for mobile Apps while managing a small remote team.

• Full Stack Developer+Team Lead | Banger Tech. Pvt. Ltd.(Doodhwala), Bangalore June 2015 - June 2017 Worked close to the co-founders being a part of a small team in this startup, created various APIs in PHP for Android and iOS Apps and created nifty admin panel to manage all ecom activities. Individually worked on products' websites and also handled a team of developers.

• Freelance Full Stack Developer and Graphic Designer

Dec 2012 - May 2015

Worked on many open and confidential projects related to device responsive website designing and development for international clients from the USA, Canada and Egypt on Elance.com and Indian clients outside Elance.

• Security Analyst Trainee | Techdefence Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, India

May 2013 - July 2013

Worked on various hacking and security techniques and tools. Got knowledge about Cyber Security, Cyber Crimes and attacks like - SQLi, XSS etc. and their prevention techniques.

• Full Stack Developer cum Trainee | Development Center - IIPS, Indore

Dec 2012 - Jan 2014

Volunteer Full Stack Developer at Development Center in IIPS-DAVV, Indore. Worked on tech projects with student teams.

PROJECTS

• Edureka Website, Admin Panel and APIs | https://www.edureka.co

Incorporated many prominent features in Edureka's website, admin panel and APIs. Helped in optimizing current tech system at various levels. Worked end-to-end from Backend to Frontend on various parts of the Apps. Technology/Tools used: CakePHP, Phalcon, PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AWS

etc.

• Trendsetter Android+iOS App API & Admin Panel

Developed APIs and sophisticated admin panel for this international project. Trendsetter provides robust mechanism to get fruitful insights of a product for which survey has to be done and enable right decision making based on the statistics generated from the targeted audience's response.

Technology/Tools used: Drupal, PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop, AWS etc.

• Doodhwala Android+iOS App API & Admin Panel

Developed backend for this popular ecommerce Android & iOS App from scratch consisting APIs, Admin Panel etc. Doodhwala App provides facility to order and get doorstep delivery of various dairy and daily use items on a subscription basis with easy to manage features and various payment options.

Technology/Tools used: PHP, MySQL, Linode, HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop etc.

• **Doodhwala website** | Hosted at http://doodhwala.com

Developed Doodhwala's earlier website featuring information about Doodhwala ecommerce product and company. Technology/Tools used: PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop etc.

• GToDo – A to-do list website

Designed and developed this micro website for personal learning by using AngularJS. This website allows to-do list creation and management. It is open source and available for learning for other developers as one of my Github repository.

Technology/Tools used: AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap etc.

• Healthoholic website

Designed and developed this website for a client. Healthoholic provides a new variety of healthy juices and along with other things.

Technology/Tools used: PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop etc.

• National Youth Festival 2015 (Pravaah) Web Application | For the year 2015

Freelancing project for Devi Ahilya University(DAVV), Indore. It is a sophisticated and device responsive web application that was used by 70+ universities across India for providing various details about their participants, managers, and accompanists. 900+ registrations took place through this application and it also aided in handling entire festival in a managed way for the very first time as the process was offline earlier.

Technology/Tools used: PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop, jQuery, and AJAX.

• **MyPlace** | Temporarily hosted at http://gauravparmar.byethost7.com/myplace/

It is my Open Source project which is available on Github. It is a small device responsive web directory for searching places, things, locations etc. with a nifty admin panel which can be expanded as a big website with data about various places (similar to JustDial).

Technology/Tools used: PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop, jQuery, and AJAX.

• IIPS College Website | For the year 2014

It is a device responsive website to represent our college IIPS-DAVV, Indore which was made in collaboration with other team members of Development Center, IIPS.

Technology/Tools used: PHP, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Git, Github etc.

• Global Harmony Fundraising

Freelancing project for a Canadian client to create a webpage to represent Global Harmony Fundraising organization and to offer registration facility. It also involved designing logo and photo collage.

Technology/Tools used: PHP, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery and Adobe Photoshop.

• PriceShaved

Freelancing project for a client from the USA. PriceShaved was a discount coupon offering website with a WordPress based Admin Panel having numerous features to manage coupons, users and other data on the website. Technology/Tools used: WordPress, Clipper Theme, WordPress Plugins, PHP, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and Adobe Photoshop.

• iQueryGRIT

This was my proposed project for Google Summer of Code(GSoC) 2015. It aimed at monitoring the health of ¡Query's repositories on Github by tracking open/closed issues, open/closed PRs, issue/PR ages etc. using Github's API. It is open source and available as my Github repository.

Technology/Tools used: Github API, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap and Adobe Photoshop.

• **SGcrypter** | Temporarily hosted at : http://gauravparmar.byethost7.com/sgcrypter/

It is a device responsive web application which I built for one of my international research paper for analysis of DES, 3DES, Blowfish and Twofish encryption/decryption algorithms by using file size, key size, encryption time and decryption time as parameters and generating graphs for various cases for easy comparison. It is open source and available as my Github repository for the use of other researchers for further research.

Technology/Tools used: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, JpGraph and Adobe Photoshop.

• Plus many other projects.

CERTIFICATE

• Certified Cyber Security Expert (CCSE) v2.0

TechDefence Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, India

Score: 90%

May 2013- July 2013

RESEARCH

Gaurav Parmar and Dr. Kirti Mathur, "Proposed Preventive Measures and Strategies Against SQL Injection Attacks", Indian Journal of Applied Research(IJAR), Vol. 5, Issue 5, pp. 716-718, May 2015, ISSN - 2249-555X

Gauray Parmar, Shaligram Prajapat, and Ramjeevan Singh Thakur, "Towards investigation of efficient cryptosystem using SGcrypter", International Conference on Computing Paradigm (ICCP) 2015 and International Journal of Applied Engineering Research (IJAER), Volume 10, Number 79 (2015), pp.853-858

- **ACHIEVEMENTS** College topper in M.Tech. with a gold medal and 9.48 CGPA.
 - Won first prize in the "Student Project Competition" organized under e-Kumbh'14 by Scientech Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Indore.
 - Won many prizes in the national level techfest "Citronics" held at CDGI, Indore in software project and website designing competition.
 - Won many prizes in website designing, coding and other technical events organized under the techno-management fest "Xpressions" held at IIPS-DAVV, Indore by leading the team in the technical pavilion.
 - Honored as "Best Student of The School" by Rotary Club, Mandsaur while studying in school.
 - Won one national level and many district level prizes in various painting competitions and have been awarded for winning painting competitions by M.P. Green Productivity Association, Swaraj Sansthan Sanchalnalay (cultural dept. of M.P. govt.), Collector of Mandsaur(M.P.), Mandsaur police etc.

OTHER INFORMATION

- Interests : Algorithms, Technical Problem Solving, Coding
- Hobbies: Solving Rubik's cube, coding, drawing & singing
- Languages known: English & Hindi
- Citizenship: India
- Relocation preference: Can relocate to a new city/country or work remotely.